A Finding Aid to the Lee Nordness business records and papers, circa 1931-1992 (bulk 1954-1984), in the Archives of American Art AAA.nordlee
Archives of American Art
Lee Nordness business records and papers
bulk 1954-1984
circa 1931-1992
AAA.nordlee
Archives of American Art
117.4 Linear feet Boxes 1-121
The Lee Nordness business records and papers measure 117.4 linear feet and date from circa 1931 to 1992 with the bulk of materials dating from 1954 to 1984. The records document seven New York City art-related companies with which Nordness was involved: Talent Discovery Company, The Little Studio, Ltd., American Art Expositions, Inc., Nordness Gallery, Inc., Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc., and Forms & Objects, Inc. Records include correspondence, artist's files, business and legal records, inventories, financial and sales records, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographic materials. Also found is a small group of personal papers.
Nordness, Lee
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., circa 1938-1992, bulk 1958-1982 (67.8 linear feet; Boxes 1-67, 117-119)
Series 2: Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc., 1938-1985 (25.4 linear feet; Boxes 68-93, 120)
Series 3: Forms & Objects, Inc., circa 1931, circa 1959-1984 (13.5 linear feet; Boxes 93-106, 120)
Series 4: American Art Expositions, Inc., 1955-1968 (1.4 linear feet; Boxes 106-107)
Series 5: The Little Studio, Inc., 1947-1969 (7.7 linear feet; Boxes 108-115, 121)
Series 6: Talent Discovery Company, 1953-1957 (0.9 linear feet; Boxes 115-116, 121)
Series 7: Personal Papers of Lee Nordness, 1948-1976 (0.7 linear feet; Box 116)
Biographical/Historical note
New York City gallerist and entrepreneur Lee Nordness (1922-1995) was born in Olympia, Washington. He studied art in college and received a bachelor's degree from Uppsala University in Sweden. From 1954-1956, Nordness ran a small gallery, Talent Discovery Company, out of his apartment in New York City. Around 1955, Nordness became the director of The Little Studio, Ltd., a gallery started by Richard Kollmer in 1952 to showcase moderately priced artwork by young artists. Nordness took over the business in 1957; it closed in April 1963.
In 1958, Nordness incorporated American Art Expositions, Inc. to organize Art:USA:58, a large exposition of contemporary American art held at Madison Square Garden. The following year Art:USA:59 was held at the New York Coliseum.
Lee Nordness opened his own gallery, Nordness Gallery, Inc., in December 1957 on Madison Avenue. The gallery promoted a roster of contemporary painters and sculptors, including David Aronson, Al Blaustein, Alberto Collie, Ralston Crawford, Robert D'Arista, Kahlil Gibran, Ruth Gikow, Peter Grippe, Milton Hebald, Zubel Kachadoorian, James Kearns, Julian Levi, Walter Meigs, Gregorio Prestopino, Hiram Williams, Karl Zerbe, and the estates of Louis Guglielmi and Rico Lebrun. In 1966, Lee Nordness reorganized his businesses. He closed Nordness Gallery and opened Lee Nordness Art Advisory Section, an art consulting service to corporations, collectors, museums, and individuals, and Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Sections, Inc. to handle exhibitions and the sale of paintings and sculptures.
Lee Nordness had an interest in American crafts and, beginning in 1968, he added a permanent roster of American craftmakers to exhibit alongside paintings and sculpture. He opened Forms & Objects, Inc. to handle the exhibition and sales of fine crafts such as ceramics, fiber, glass, metal and wood. With a need for additional exhibition space, the gallery moved a few blocks off Madison Avenue to 236-238 East 75th Street.
Nordness traveled the globe to assemble prominent collections for clients, such as Art:USA, a collection of contemporary works by 102 American artists for S.C. Johnson & Son, Inc. Art:USA traveled throughout the United States and Europe in the mid-late 1960s before being donated to the National Collection of Fine Arts (Smithsonian Institution). In the late 1960s, he assembled a collection of 300 American craft objects for S.C. Johnson & Son, Inc. called Objects:USA, which toured throughout the United States and Europe. This collection was disassembled in the late 1970s, many of the works donated to the Museum of Arts and Design, formerly the Museum of Contemporary Craft.
Nordness closed his New York galleries in the mid-1980s. Soon after, he moved to Belfair, Washington and opened Lee Nordness Galleries, Inc. in 1986. He passed away in 1995 in Washington.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Lee Nordness business records and papers were donated to the Archives of American Art in several increments by Lee Nordness in 1976, 1986 and as a bequest in 1996. Original materials were also lent by Nordness in 1964 and 1969 for microfilming, some of which may have been included in subsequent donations.
Scope and Contents note
The Lee Nordness business records and papers measure 117.4 linear feet and date from circa 1931 to 1992 with the bulk of materials dating from 1954 to 1984. The records document seven New York City art-related companies with which Nordness was involved: Talent Discovery Company, The Little Studio, Ltd., American Art Expositions, Inc., Nordness Gallery, Inc., Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc., and Forms & Objects, Inc. Records include correspondence, artist's files, business and legal records, inventories, financial and sales records, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographic materials. Also found is a small group of personal papers.
More than half of the collection documents Lee Nordness' primary businesses, Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc. Business correspondence, artist's files, extensive project files, business and legal records, financial and sales records, inventories, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographic materials reveal Nordness' role as an art dealer of contemporary American artwork and art consultant to companies and organizations. The records document his ability to adapt to changing external markets as well as his own interests, from dealing primarily in paintings and sculpture to promoting American fine crafts. Artists from Nordness' permanent roster are represented, including David Aronson, Al Blaustein, Alberto Collie, Ralston Crawford, Robert D'Arista, Kahlil Gibran, Ruth Gikow, Peter Grippe, Louis Guglielmi, Milton Hebald, Zubel Kachadoorian, James Kearns, Rico Lebrun, Julian Levi, Walter Meigs, Gregorio Prestopino, Hiram Williams, and Karl Zerbe. Companies and organizations represented include S.C. Johnson & Son, Co., Metromedia, and Cooper-Hewitt, National Museum of Design. Because materials from Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Art Advisory Section were often interfiled and related, the records were not separated into different series.
The records of Lee Nordness Galleries Exhibition Section, Inc. document the exhibition and sale of artwork through correspondence, artist's files, business records, financial and sales records, and scrapbooks for artists and exhibition seasons. Forms & Objects, Inc. contains correspondence, lecture notes, public relations files, business records, financial and sales records, scrapbooks and photographic materials related to American fine crafts.
The organization and press surrounding the monumental exhibitions Art:USA:58 and Art:USA:59 are illustrated in the correspondence, banking records, founding documents, newspaper clippings, paid bill receipts, and sales invoices of the American Art Expositions, Inc. records. Photographs of the Art:USA:59 artists taken by Fred Darrah are also found here.
The bulk of the records of The Little Studio, Inc. are financial records and sales invoices. Lee Nordness' involvement in the gallery is also documented through correspondence and business records. The records of Talent Discovery Company are primarily financial, including banking records, receipts, and tax records. Also found are shipping records, correspondence, and inventory cards.
There are few personal papers of Lee Nordness, the bulk of which are related to his involvement with his tenant cooperative. Also found is scattered correspondence, a scrapbook, and travel documents.
Records for the various companies were co-mingled upon accession. AAA has attempted to place papers in Nordness' original order based on discussions with Nordness and evidence from the records. However, researchers should note there is significant interfiling of the companies' records throughout the collection, especially scrapbooks and photographs. Researchers are strongly encouraged to use dates and keywords to help discover related materials throughout all series.
Abbreviations were often written by the gallery in the upper left-hand corner of a document to indicate to which company the record should be filed. Abbreviations used include: Nordness Gallery, "NG" or "LN"; Art Advisory Section, "AA" or "LN"; Exhibition Section, "ES" or "E/S"; Forms & Objects, "F/O"; American Art Expositions, "AAE"; The Little Studio, "TLS"; and, Talent Discovery Company, "TDC."
Separated Materials note
Three microfilm reels of material were loaned to the Archives of American Art by Lee Nordness in 1959 regarding American Art Exposition, Inc.'s Art:USA 58 and Art:USA:59. Microfilm includes correspondence, catalogs, visitor lists, press releases, lists of artwork, financial records, and advertising materials and is available on reels NAU1, NAU2 and NAU3.
Later, in 1964 and 1969, Lee Nordness loaned original materials for microfilming compiled by Nordness Gallery about the careers of Gregorio Prestopino, Julian E. Levi, and Lee Gatch, including correspondence, exhibition materials, biographical information, clippings, and photographs. Loaned material is available on reels N69-21 and D169. Original materials were returned to Nordness, but some may have been included in later donations and those originals have been integrated with the other donated records.
The contents of microfilm reels are not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
American Art Expositions. (New York, N.Y.); Aronson, David, 1923-; Blaustein, Al H., 1924-2004; Collie, Alberto; Cooper-Hewitt Museum.; Crawford, Ralston, 1906-1978; D'Arista, Robert, 1929-; Forms and Objects. (Firm); Gibran, Kahlil, 1922-; Gikow, Ruth, 1915-1982; Grippe, Peter, 1912-; Guglielmi, Louis, 1906-1956; Hebald, Milton; Johnson Wax.; Kachadoorian, Zubel, 1924-; Kearns, James; Lebrun, Rico, 1900-1964; Lee Nordness Galleries; Levi, Julian E. (Julian Edwin), 1900-1982; Little Studio.; Meigs, Walter, 1918-1988; Metromedia, Inc.; Nordness Gallery.; Prestopino, Gregorio; Talent Discovery Company.; Williams, Hiram; Zerbe, Karl, 1903-1972; Art dealers--New York (State)--New York; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Section, Inc., bulk 1958-1982; circa 1938-1992; Series 1; 67.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-67, 117-119
  Scope and Contents note
  The records of Nordness Gallery, Inc. and Lee Nordness Galleries Art Advisory Services, Inc. document the exhibitions and sales of artwork of the galleries' artists, and the development and organization of various projects with corporations and museums through correspondence, artist's files, project files, business and legal records, financial and sales records, inventories, printed materials, scrapbooks, and photographic materials.
  Because materials from Nordness Gallery and Art Advisory Section were frequently interfiled, the records are found together in one series. In addition, "Nordness Gallery" was occasionally used on letterhead and legal documents after it had closed. Researchers should use dates and context as necessary to discover related materials.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 10 subseries:
  1.1: Correspondence, 1950-1992
  1.2: Artist's Files, circa 1938-1985, bulk 1968-1982
  1.3: Project Files, 1952-1990
  1.4: Business Records, 1955-1986
  1.5: Legal Records, 1950s-1979
  1.6: Financial and Sales Records, 1954-1992
  1.7: Inventory Records, circa 1958-1980
  1.8: Printed Materials, 1960-1980s
  1.9: Scrapbooks, circa 1940s-1980s
  1.10: Photographic Materials, circa 1940-1980s
  - Correspondence, 1950-1992; 1.1
    This subseries includes business correspondence with museums, galleries, businesses, artists and others regarding sales, exhibitions, and other business matters.
    Chronological correspondence is arranged first, followed by folders arranged alphabetically correspondent's name or subject.
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
    - Chronological Correspondence (1964), 1962-1964; 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7-26)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27-30)
    - Adamiak, Joe, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Adams, Robert, 1963-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Albericci, Jo, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - American Art Expositions, Inc., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Americana, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Amon-Carter Museum, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Ankrum Gallery, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Appraisals, 1973; 1976; 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Architects, Martin J. Hyman and Paul Thompson, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Arleigh Gallery, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Art Dealers Association of America, Inc., 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
    - Art Gallery, University of Singapore, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Art Gallery Unlimited, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Art in Embassies, 1964-1968; 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
    - Art Organizations, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - Art Project Letters, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Artist Information Requests, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Artists, 1988-1991; 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 28-36)
    - Artists' Greetings Cards, circa 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Artists (Box 3)
      - Pending, 1953; 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Pending, Dimitri Hadzi, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Possibilities, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Prospective, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Rejected, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Arwin Galleries, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Joan Avnet Galleries, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - N.W. Ayer & Sons, Inc., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bank Job, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bayroff Gallery, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Birsh, Arthur T., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Blondelle, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Bolles Gallery, 1969; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Brockman Gallery, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Butler, Eugenie and Riko Mizuno (Gallery 669), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Carl Byoir & Associates, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cables and Telegrams, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cafe Carnegie, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - The Cannery Gallery, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Caracas, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Carlin Galleries, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Catalogs, 1964; 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 26-28)
    - Catalogs, Comments, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Catalogs, Copy, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - The Cellar Gallery (Minneapolis), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Le Centre D'Art, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Certificates of Originality, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Chatham Galleries, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Cirker's Hayes Storage Warehouse, 1972-1976; 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
    - Claims, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Geoffrey Clements, Inc., 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - The A.B. Closson, Jr. Co., 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - David Cole Gallery, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Collections, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Collectors, 1958-1968 (Box 3, Folder 43-46)
    - Columbia Museum of Art, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Comara Gallery (Walter Meigs), 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Con Edison, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Contemporaries Galleries, 1963; 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Museum of Contemporary Crafts, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Corporation Pitch Letters for Art Projects, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Craftsmen, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Critics, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cseh, Irene von/Jo Albericci, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Customs, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Laura Dee Advertising, 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Department Stores - World's Fair, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Diners Club International, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Donner, M., circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Downtown Gallery, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - Dudchenko, Boris, circa 1974 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Einschreiben Recommended, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Elan Construction, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Empire State Travel, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Gallerie Espace NY, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Rex Evans Gallery, 1964; 1969 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Exhibitions, Charity, 1958-1970 (Box 4, Folder 23-29)
    - Exhibitions, European, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Exhibitions, Gallery and Consignment, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 31-33)
    - Exhibitions, Guest Artists, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 34-36)
    - Exhibitions, Museums, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
    - Exhibitions, Museums, 1958; 1960-1965 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
    - Exhibitions, Out of Gallery, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Exhibitions, Possible Museums and Galleries for Touring Exhibits, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Fairweather-Hardin Gallery, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Feuillatte, Nicholas, Jean Appel & Co., 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Fine Arts in Living" Exhibition, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Fischmann & Weiner Gallery, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Ford Foundation, 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
    - Forrest Sign Co., 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Fountain Gallery of Art, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Franchise Concepts, Inc., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Freedman & Slater, Inc., 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Friends of the Whitney Museum of American Art, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
    - Future Business, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Galleries, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
    - The Gallery of Modern Art (Scottsdale, AZ), 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Garrell, Louis, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Gettings, Frank, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Gifts, Charity, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Guest Artists, 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - Guggenheim Museum, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Gump's, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Hague Art Deliveries, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hanes, R. Philip, Jr., 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Hansen Galleries, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Harmon Gallery, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Heritage Gallery, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hill, Tim, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - Holdaway and Company, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hollis Galleries, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hultberg, Peter [Miscellaneous framing and shipping invoices], 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - G.T. Hunter Gallery, 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Huszar, John, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Universidad Iberoamericana Museum, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Image Gallery, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Indianapolis Museum of Art, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Insurance, 1958-1959; 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Interoffice Correspondence, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Invitations, 1962-1963; 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Isaacs Gallery, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Issa Art Gallery, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Ivonc, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - James, Stephen, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Japan, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Japan, Tokyo Gallery, circa 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Johnson, Karen Keland, Acquisitions, 1979; 1976 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Johnson, Samuel, 1991; 1973-1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, Samuel and Gene, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - The Johnson Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - The Johnson Foundation, National Jazz Service Organization, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Johnson Wax, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Johnson Wax (Box 6)
      - Hart, Bob (Attorney, S.C. Johnson & Co.), 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Johnson, H.F. (Chairman Emeritus), 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Johnson, Samuel (President, S.C. Johnson & Son), 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
      - The Johnson Foundation, 1967-1974 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Jones, E.O. (Public Relations, S.C. Johnson & Son), 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 37-38)
      - Martin, Tom (Vice President, S.C. Johnson & Son), 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 39-41)
      - Seiser, Neal (Public Relations, S.C. Johnson & Son), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Johnson Wax European, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Jurying, 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 44-45)
    - Kasmin Limited, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Keland, Karen, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Atelier Chapman Kelley, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Kilgore, John, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Kleete, circa 1980s-1991 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Kleinbardt, Ruth, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Koffler, Robert S., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Kovler Gallery, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Krannert Art Museum, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Krap ["News From the Art World" Newsletter], 1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Oscar Krasner, Inc., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Galerie Krikhaar, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Labor of Industries, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Felix Landau Gallery, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Larsen, Yvonne, 1966-1977 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - Little Gallery, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - London Gallery, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Los Angeles County Museum, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Lowell, George, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - A. Lublin, Inc., 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Magazines, Books and Catalogs, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Manhattan Storage, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Mason County Assessor, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - McCulloch, Robert, Jr., 1968-1977 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Messing, Job (Notes to), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Metromedia and Pat Peterson, circa 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Mickelson Gallery, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Milan Exchange, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
    - Minami Gallery, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - The Mint Museum of Art, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Boris Mirski Gallery, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969-1991 (Box 7, Folder 30-33)
    - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co., 1970-1980 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Morgan Manhattan Storage, 1963-1968 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Morgan Manhattan Storage Accounts #1-2, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 36-37)
    - Museum Gallery Sales, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Museum Loans, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Museum Sales Completed, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Museum Tours, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Museums, 1958-1967 (Box 7, Folder 42-48)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, LA Symposium, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - New Gallery [831 Madison Ave.], 1950-1960 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - New Gallery, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Newark Museums, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 52)